Okay, so there's just a
couple of additional Agile
terms I just want to
mention in this section.
First of all, validate scope, right?
You might come across this term.
Now, validate scope is actually one of the
old Pinbox six processes, right?
But if you ever come across this term,
this is basically the process of
formalizing the acceptance of the
deliverable, right?
Who accepts a deliverable?
The customer.
Right.
So validate scope is basically performed
by the customer.
So it's a customer that is going to accept
the deliverable.
So once we have created the product,
or we meaning the project team,
once we've created the product,
and then we've tested it, now we give it
to the customer for their testing,
right, for their sign off.
Think of, say, user acceptance testing.
customer is going to
test it, and then they're
going to approve it or reject it, right?
They're going to approve it or reject it.
They're going to accept it.
And that's what validate scope is.
So to some extent, you could think of it
as user acceptance testing.
Validate scope is basically, as I said,
the customer's acceptance.
The customer has to
accept that final deliverable,
right, before we can
basically go into closing.
Before we can close out the project,
close out the contract, close out the
contract, close out the you know that kind
of thing right so as again as a very
simple example right you're doing some
work in your house something very simple
right you've hired some contractors to do
some work in your house right so while
they are performing the work what you're
doing as a as a customer you're walking
around seeing how the work is progressing
right now they put in the right walls in
the right places and put the right
cabinets on the right walls and you know
the right colors on the right walls and so
and so forth right you're seeing seeing
how they're progressing are
Are they doing the work that
they're supposed to be doing
that you wanted them to do?
Are they meeting your expectations,
your requirements and so and so forth?
So what are you doing?
You are validating scope, right?
So validate scope is something that the
customer does, right?
And it's a customer that determines the
acceptance criteria.
The customer is the one that is accepting
the product.
The customer is the one that is saying,
does this meet our requirements?
Not the team.
The customer is the one that has a final
say.
Now, if there is a dispute, we need to
resolve that dispute.
It might need to go through a change
control.
In an agile environment, validate scope
would be your sprint review meeting.
Remember, in the
sprint review meeting, the
team is delivering the
product to the customer.
And the customer, in this case,
being the product owner.
So it's a product owner.
then who is going to be signing off on the
deliverable.
And in fact, that is what is documented
here.
The next slide here, right?
Iteration review or sprint review.
Right.
Now, the sprint review is an agile
ceremony.
You know, we've mentioned this in other
videos as well.
And it's where the agile
team now is presenting
the deliverable to the product toner.
Remember, the product toner is voice of
the customer, right?
They represent the customer.
So the Agile team, they present what they
delivered during the sprint, and it's a
product owner then that is going to accept
it or reject it.
So this would be then the validate scope
process, if you like, in
an agile environment.
Again, remember, validate scope is always
the customer's acceptance.
Another term we'll come across is this one
called a variance analysis, and a variance
is just a difference being planned and
actual.
This is what we should have done,
this is what we actually did.
why is there a discrepancy, right?
That discrepancy then is variance.
I mean, variance means a difference,
right?
So, are we headed schedule?
Are we behind schedule?
Are we over budget?
Are we under budget?
Right, we should have spent this much.
We only spent this much.
Right.
So we should have spent $20,000 so far to
get this work.
We've only spent $15,000.
Great, we've only spent $5,000 under
budget.
Right.
Or more than likely, we should have spent
$20,000.
We've spent $25,000 with $5,000 over
budget.
So that's what the variance analysis is.
difference in the plan and the actual.
And trend analysis refers to basically
which way are we trending, right?
So is the performance improving or
worsening over time?
Right.
So we're behind schedule right now.
Are we getting further and further behind
schedule?
Is that what our assumption is?
So the trend is always looking ahead,
looking forward.
So are we improving?
Are we decreasing?
right.
So like said, we're behind schedule right
now.
Are we going to continue going further and
further behind schedule?
Are we over budget?
Are we going to continue getting further
and further over budget?
Right.
So that's really what trend analysis is,
which way are we
trending right now, right?
Is the performance improving?
Is it getting better?
Let me start that again.
Is it is improving or is it worsening?
So these were just a couple of additional
terms that I just wanted to mention,
just in case you see them on the exam.
So now you know what those terms are.